

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

💌 danielober84@gmail.com 🚱 www.danielober.com/ 📞 (508) 446-6548 💡 Nashville, TN 37211

SUMMARY

I'm a full-stack web developer with a background in customer success and technical support. As a recent software engineer immersive graduate, I'm excited to combine my web development knowledge with the skills and experience from my previous career as a Manager of Customer Success. With the ability to build strong teams in a cross-functional environment, I embrace the leadership skills I've learned by leading with passion, empathy, and a "stay curious" mindset.

SKILLS

HTML5, CSS, Javascript, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, jQuery, Git, REST API, Axios Leadership, Customer Satisfaction, Account Management, Marketing Strategy, Sales, Product Development, Time Management, Team Building, CRM, Social Media, Entrepreneurship Visual Studio Code, Sublime, Postman, Postico, GitHub, Microsoft Excel, Google Sheets, Slack, Logic X

EXPERIENCE

GENERAL ASSEMBLY, Software Engineering Immersive

Dec. 2020 - Apr. 2021

- Software engineering immersive bootcamp, over 500+ hours of practical application in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ruby, React, Mongoose, Express, Rails, MongoDB, Postgres, APIs, and other development tools.
- Completed in-class projects, hackathons, and personal projects focused on real-world applications of principles and best practices.

JUMPCREW, Client Success Manager, Nashville, TN

Feb. 2020 - July 2020

- · Managed client relationships, communications, results, and engagements, while minimizing client retention
- Provided clients with accurate monthly/quarterly sales forecasting, consultative reviews, reporting and health-checks on a weekly, monthly, and quarterly basis
- · Ensured that all delivery team members were striving towards achieving their KPIs and success metrics established for each client

SMILE DIRECT CLUB, Sales Associate, Nashville, TN

Dec. 2019 - Feb. 2020

- Utilized consultative selling techniques to present key selling points, features and benefits while remaining focused on customers' needs and expectations
- · Demonstrated persistence and achieved objections, while improving individual skills and overall sales performance
- Effectively communicated and built relationships with customers to provide a world class customer experience
- Executed the entire Retainer sale approach from opening to close

CARGURUS, Manager, Customer Success, Cambridge, MA

July 2017 - Aug. 2019

- · Managed daily operations, while leading and motivating a team of 20+ to ensure outstanding customer support
- · Built out a Customer Support function in a start-up environment, including all of Support policies, procedures, KPI's, knowledge base, and team vision
- Used analytical and problem solving skills to identify trends, possible solutions, and recommendations for significant, or emerging, support events to deliver operational efficiencies and an improved customer experience
- · Planned for growth of customer base, product offerings, and team development to prepare and optimize for CarGurus' continued success
- CarGurus President's Club Award, 2017
- Maintained a CSAT score of 90% overall in 2019

Team Lead, Customer Success, Cambridge, MA

June 2016 - June 2017

- · Motivated, led, and coached a team of 16 Support agents
- Established and rolled out KPI metrics with a focus on overall throughput and quality
- QA of support cases daily, monitored agent performance, conducted one on one meetings and performance reviews
- · Built out an effective one-on-one and coaching/feedback structure between Team Lead and individual contributor

Account Manager, Cambridge, MA

Oct 2015 - Feb 2016

- Managed 250+ designated CarGurus client accounts (primarily outbound)
- Analyzed dealers' performance and provided consultation on improving lead flow/exposure on CarGurus to secure a long term relationship
- · Helped to establish growth and retention roles for existing, cancelling, and previously canceled dealerships
- · Assisted team in transition from Account Manager to an Onboarding Customer Success structure

Client Services Representative, Cambridge, MA

Jan. 2015 - Sept. 2015

- Received client inquiries regarding product functionality; determined solutions and responded in a timely and efficient manner via phone, email or webinar
- · A subject matter expert on all CarGurus products and soft-sell if a dealer makes a good candidate for other products
- Escalated unresolved client issues to respective departments
- Documented support case issues, customer communications, and resolutions using Salesforce

VOLUNTEERING

YearUp, Mentor 2015 - Aug. 2019

AWARDS

President's Club CarGurus Jan 2017

EDUCATION

General Assembly Certificate of Completion, Software Engineering 2021 Dec. 2020 - Apr. 2021

Berklee College of Music Film Scoring and Composition Sept. 2007 - June 2008

Dean College

Sept. 2005 - June 2007

Associate's Liberal Arts